Hello, welcome to Career 247, I am
नमस्कार वेलकम टू करियर 247 मैं हूं
Prashant Dhawan. See, there is a rule of geopolitics, never go
प्रशांत धवन देखिए जिओपॉलिटिक्स का एक रूल
full Pakistan, US just went
है नेवर गो फुल पाकिस्तान यूएस जस्ट वेंट
full Pakistan. Now here you will be
फुल पाकिस्तान नाउ यहां पे आप लोग देख
able to see the article, the US
पाओगे आर्टिकल पाकिस्तान के बारे में यूएस
Army General has given big statements about Pakistan, he
के आर्मी जनरल ने बड़ी स्टेटमेंट्स दी है
said that Pakistan is a phenomenal
यह कह दिया कि पाकिस्तान एक फिनोमिनल
partner in fighting terrorism and here he
पार्टनर है आतंकवाद से लड़ने में और यहां
also said that we need good relations
पर यह भी कह दिया कि हमको अच्छे रिलेशंस
with both India and Pakistan, it is
चाहिए भारत और पाकिस्तान दोनों के साथ ऐसा
not the case that in order to improve relations with India, we will
नहीं है कि भारत के साथ रिलेशंस सुधारने
spoil the relations with Pakistan.
में पाकिस्तान के साथ रिलेशंस खराब कर
We will have good relations with both of
देंगे। वी विल हैव गुड रिलेशंस विद बोथ ऑफ
them.  And these statements of the US General
देम। और ये जो स्टेटमेंट्स है यूएस जनरल
actually
की ये एक्चुअली इंडिया की बहुत सारी
completely counter many of the statements of India and the United Nations.
यूनाइटेड नेशंस की स्टेटमेंट्स को बिल्कुल
US Generals are openly
काउंटर कर देती है। यूएस जनरल ओपनली
defending Pakistan.  It was even said
पाकिस्तान को डिफेंड कर रहे हैं। यह तक कह
that Pakistan's record
दिया कि पाकिस्तान का रिकॉर्ड आतंकवाद से
in fighting terrorism is very good and after this a
लड़ने में बहुत अच्छा है और इसके बाद एक
report also comes that the current
रिपोर्ट ये भी आती है कि पाकिस्तान के अभी
Army Chief of Pakistan, Asim Munir, has now become the
जो आर्मी चीफ हैं आसिम मुनीर जो अब बन
Field Marshal of Pakistan.
चुके हैं फील्ड मार्शल ऑफ पाकिस्तान।
They will be invited to the US for
इन्हें यूएस में इनवाइट किया जाएगा फॉर
Trump's Military Day Parade.  This is a very
ट्रम्प्स मिलिट्री डे परेड। यह एक बहुत ही
important symbolic gesture.  I
इंपॉर्टेंट सिंबॉलिक जेस्चर है। मैंने
told you in a very important
आपको बताया था एक बहुत ही इंपॉर्टेंट
video.  I don't know why this video didn't get so many views.
वीडियो में। इस वीडियो को इतने व्यूज मिले
But this was really an
नहीं पता नहीं क्यों। बट दिस वाज़ सच एन
important video.  In this I
इंपॉर्टेंट वीडियो। मैंने इसमें आपको
explained to you that Trump literally
समझाया था कि ट्रंप ने लिटरली पाकिस्तान
saved Pakistan from a travel ban.  And
को बचा लिया फ्रॉम अ ट्रैवल बैन। और उसके
apart from that why today the money Bitcoin is
अलावा क्यों आज के समय पैसा बिटकॉइन एक
playing a critical role
क्रिटिकल रोल प्ले कर रहा है डॉनल्ड ट्रंप
in the pro-Pakistan policies of Donald Trump.  And you have to
की प्रो पाकिस्तान पॉलिसीज में। और आप एक
note one thing, Donald Trump is constantly
बात नोट करना कांस्टेंटली डॉनल्ड ट्रंप
praising the leadership of Pakistan.
पाकिस्तान की जो लीडरशिप है इसकी तारीफ
Many videos have surfaced in
करते जा रहे हैं। कई वीडियोस सामने आई है
which Trump has said, I know some
जहां पे ट्रंप ने बोला है मुझे पता है कुछ
people don't like it when I
लोगों को अच्छा नहीं लगता जब मैं यह बात
say this.  But the leadership of Pakistan is very
बोलता हूं। मगर पाकिस्तान की लीडरशिप बहुत
good.  You should watch this clip and then
अच्छी है। ये जो क्लिप है ये आप देखिए फिर
we will talk about the rest of the developments that are taking place today.  Obviously all this has
इस पे हम बात करेंगे। ऑब्वियसली इस सब का
a very deep link with the F35.
एक बहुत ही गहरा लिंक है F35 से। F35
Very important developments are taking place related to the F35 fighter jet.
फाइटर जेट से रिलेटेड बहुत ही इंपॉर्टेंट
Many
डेवलपमेंट्स हो रही हैं। बहुतेंट
articles are being published.  I will
आर्टिकल्स पब्लिश हो रहे हैं। वो भी मैं
show you that as well.  But just have a view of
आपको दिखाऊंगा। बट जस्ट हैव अ व्यू के
what statements Donald Trump has given lately
डोनाल्ड ट्रंप लेटली क्या स्टेटमेंट्स दे
about Pakistan.
चुके हैं पाकिस्तान के बारे में।
And Pakistan like wise they
एंड पाकिस्तान लाइक वाइज दे
leadership near like when I say.
लीडरशिप समीप लाइक व्हेन आई से।
Now this statement was by US President
नाउ ये स्टेटमेंट थी यूएस प्रेसिडेंट
Donald Trump.  Now you will see
डोनाल्ड ट्रंप की। अब आप देखोगे यूएस के
what statement the Army General of the US Central Command will
सेंट्रल कमांड के जो आर्मी जनरल यह क्या
give, regarding Pakistan,
स्टेटमेंट देंगे रिगार्डिंग पाकिस्तान
this is a very important video, it
बहुत इंपॉर्टेंट वीडियो है यह रिसेंटली
also went viral recently in the Indian diplomatic
काफी वायरल भी हुई थी इंडियन डिप्लोमेटिक
circles, you will be able to see it here,
सर्कल्स में यहां पे आप देख पाओगे
but most active to do externally globally,
पर मोस्ट एक्टिव टू डू एक्सटर्नल ग्लोबली
if
अगर
I there put there
आई देदर पुट देर
Pakistan border
पाकिस्तान बॉर्डर
partnership, Pakistan gave after ice to them
पार्टनरशिप पाकिस्तान देव गॉन आफ्टर आइस
relationship, we have them providing
देम रिलेशनशिप वी हैव देम प्रोवाइडिंग
intelligence, they have captured at least five
इंटेलिजेंस दे हैव कैप्चर एटलीस्ट फाइव
ice Kosan high individuals, they are extra
आइस कोसान हाई इंडिविजुअल्स दे एक्स्ट्रा
back Zafar, who is one of the key individuals
बैक जफार हु वन ऑफ़ द की इंडिविजुअल्स
behind the egging, now this Zafar, about whom we are talking, is a
बिहाइंड द एगिंग नाउ ये जफार जिसकी बात कर
terrorist who was handed
रहे हैं ये आतंकवादी है जो पाकिस्तान ने
back by Pakistan to the US, I will admit that
वापस यूएस को पकड़ा दिया था मैं ये एडमिट
Pakistan has figured out
करूंगा पाकिस्तान को पता लगा कि डोनल्ड
how to please Donald Trump?  Whether it's
ट्रंप ट्रंप को खुश कैसे करना है? चाहे वह
from bitcoin investments or just a
बिटकॉइन इन्वेस्टमेंट से हो या फिर कोई एक
random terrorist getting caught.  It was immediately
रैंडम आतंकवादी पकड़ लिया। उसी वक्त यूएस
sent to the US and this gave Donald Trump an
को भेज दिया और डोनल्ड ट्रंप को इससे एक
opportunity to say that look, we have
बोलने का मौका मिल गया कि देखो हमने एक
caught a terrorist here.  Pakistan
आतंकवादी यहां पे पकड़ लिया है। पाकिस्तान
is playing USA very well.  But
काफी अच्छा प्ले कर रहा है यूएसए को। बट
USA clearly is now adopting a pro-Pakistan
यूएसए क्लियरली यह जो अब प्रो पाकिस्तान
approach, it might
अप्रोच ये अपना रहे हैं ना इट माइट बैक
backfire big time.  Because just today the FBI
फायर बिग टाइम। क्योंकि आज ही एफबीआई के
chief Kash Patel gave a statement
जो चीफ है कश पटेल इन्होंने एक स्टेटमेंट
that a man from Pakistan was about to carry out a
दी कि एक पाकिस्तान का आदमी यूएसए में
major terrorist attack in the USA and he was
बड़ा आतंकवादी हमला करने वाला था इसको
stopped.  Here you will see that this is the same country
रोका गया। यह इधर आप देख पाओगे वही देश
which the US is saying is a very much
जिसको यूएस कह रहा है कि जी बहुत ज्यादा
a USA friendly country and
एक यू नो फ्रेंडली कंट्री है यूएसए का
will help USA in fighting terrorism.  FBI
आतंकवाद से लड़ने को हेल्प करेगा। एफबीआई
Director Kash Patel has said that major news
डायरेक्टर कश पटेल ने कहा है मेजर न्यूज़
earlier this afternoon, Mohammad Shahzab Khan,
अर्लियर दिस आफ्टरनून मोहम्मद शहजाब खान
a Pakistani citizen, again this is the official
एक पाकिस्तानी सिटीजन अगेन यह ऑफिशियल
tweet by the FBI Director Kash Patel,
ट्वीट है बाय द एफबीआई डायरेक्टर कश पटेल
a Pakistani citizen who was living in Canada was
एक पाकिस्तानी सिटीजन जो कनाडा में रह रहा
extradited from the USA
था इसको एक्स्ट्राइट किया गया था यूएसए
on charges of attempting to provide
में ऑन चार्जेस ऑफ अटेमप्टिंग टू प्रोवाइड
material support to ISIS. Now imagine, the
मटेरियल सपोर्ट टू आइसिस अब सोच कर देखिए
Army Chief of the US Central Command says
यूएस सेंट्रल कमांड का आर्मी चीफ कहता है
that Pakistan is
कि जी आइसिस से लड़ने के लिए पाकिस्तान
helping them to fight ISIS, on the other hand, a
इनकी हेल्प कर रहा है दूसरी तरफ एक
Pakistani citizen sitting in Canada, where,
पाकिस्तानी सिटीजन कनाडा में बैठकर जहां
as you know, there are
पे कनाडा में आप जैसे ही आपको पता है
a lot of NTD activities in Canada.
एनटीडी एक्टिविटीज बहुत ज्यादा होती हैं।
There it is supporting ISIS
वहां पर यह आइसिस का सपोर्ट कर रहा है
so that terrorism can be carried out.  Here you
ताकि आतंकवाद किया जा सके। इधर आप देख
can see in the fall last year Khan legitimately
पाओगे इन द फॉल लास्ट ईयर खान एलिजिडली
planned to travel from Canada to New York
प्लान टू ट्रैवल फ्रॉम कनाडा टू न्यूयॉर्क
to carry out a mass shooting in support of
टू कैरी आउट ए मास शूटिंग इन सपोर्ट ऑफ
ISS at a JASS center in Brooklyn.  This is the
आईएसएस एट ए जस सेंटर इन ब्रोकलिन। यह
condition of Pakistan that such people are coming out from here
हालत है पाकिस्तान की कि यहां से ऐसे लोग
who are going to carry out such attacks in the USA.
निकल रहे हैं जो यूएसए में इस टाइप के
And I
अटैक करने वाले हैं। और मुझे
have to say unfortunately.  I mean it seems
अनफॉर्चुनेटली बोलना पड़ेगा। आई मीन लग
that the US will learn from a big mistake
रहा है कि यूएस एक बड़ी मिस्टेक करके
because the problem with the US is that
सीखेगा क्योंकि यूएस की प्रॉब्लम यह है यह
they start to believe from one or two gestures from Pakistan that the
लोग पाकिस्तान के एक दो जेस्चर से ना यह
terrorists and the fundamentalists in Pakistan are
में आतंकवाद और जो फंडामेंटलिस्ट जो ये
different and their army and
लोग हैं ये अलग हैं और जो इनकी आर्मी है
their government are different.  Whereas the
और जो इनकी सरकार है वो अलग है। जबकि
images of funerals that have emerged after Operation Sindoor are from Pakistan.  This
इमेजेस सामने आई है पाकिस्तान से। दिस
clearly proves their army and their government.
क्लियरली प्रूव्स इनकी आर्मी इनकी सरकार।
All these people support the terrorists.  It is
यह सब लोग आतंकवादियों को सपोर्ट करते
not that
हैं। कोई ऐसा नहीं है कि अलग है कुछ
Pakistan's army is different.  I mean
पाकिस्तान की आर्मी। आई मीन यह बात
Indians know this.
इंडियंस को पता है। इवन अफगानिस्तान में
Even the peace loving people in Afghanistan know this.
भी जो पीस लविंग लोग हैं उनको भी पता है।
I would say that the US is about to make a huge
ये मैं कहूंगा यूएस एक बहुत ही बड़ा
strategic blunder.  And if
स्ट्रेटेजिक ब्लंडर करने वाला है। और अगर
you are asking why US can make such a blunder
आप पूछ रहे हैं यूएस ऐसा ब्लंडर क्यों कर
?  I think, somewhere in this, they are
सकता है? आई थिंक इसमें कहीं ना कहीं यह
also giving a little reply to India by
इंडिया को ना एक थोड़ा सा रिप्लाई भी दे
improving relations with Pakistan.  The
रहे हैं पाकिस्तान के साथ रिलेशंस इंप्रूव
reason behind this is simple.  Now see,
करके। रीजन इसका सिंपल है। अब देखिए
slowly this news has started coming from India
धीरे-धीरे इंडिया से यह न्यूज़ आनी
that India is not going to purchase F35.
स्टार्ट हो चुकी है कि F35 भारत परचेस
I had told you earlier also
नहीं करने वाला। मैंने आपको पहले भी कहा
that Donald Trump must have been informed about this long
था कि डॉनल्ड ट्रंप को इसके बारे में काफी
ago and that is why he is continuously
पहले बता दिया गया हो और इसलिए लगातार यह
giving absurd statements
उल्टी सीधी स्टेटमेंट्स दे रहे हैं कश्मीर
about Kashmir.  About India Pakistan relations
के बारे में। इंडिया पाकिस्तान रिलेशंस के
because USA had made a heavy push
बारे में क्योंकि यूएसए ने काफी हैवी पुश
for F35 Farjet.  So
किया था F35 फरजेट के लिए। तो F35 को
India is not even considering this proposal to acquire F35.  The talk is
इंडिया कंसीडर तक नहीं कर रहा। बात यह चल
that either we will build the AMCA faster
रही है कि या तो हम एएमसीए को और तेजी से
and at the same time
बिल्ड करेंगे और साथ ही साथ हो सकता है कि
we may acquire Russian SU 57 fighter jets.
रशियन एसयू 57 फाइटर जेट्स हमें एक्वायर
Look, this will be considered
करें। यह देखिए डोन्ड ट्रंप की
a big blunder on the part of Donald Trump's administration
एडमिनिस्ट्रेशन की तरफ से एक बड़ा ब्लंडर
that it could not convince India to
माना जाएगा कि इंडिया को मना नहीं पाई है
purchase F35.  India is again going to
कि F35 परचेस करो। इंडिया फिर से लार्ज
purchase Russian weapons on a large scale
स्केल पर रशियन वेपंस परचेस करने वाला है
and this deal is going to be a mega deal
और यह तो खैर जो डील होगी एक मेगा डील
and the impact of this deal will be felt in the region for many years,
होने वाली है और कई सालों तक इस डील का
so now
इंपैक्ट महसूस किया जाएगा रीजन पे तो अभी
see in the coming times, to
तो आने वाले समय में देखिए थोड़ा सा
tell India also that now it is
इंडिया को भी यू नो बताने के लिए के अब
okay, then Pakistan is also as important for us
ठीक है फिर पाकिस्तान भी हमारे लिए उतना
as India is important.
इंपॉर्टेंट है जितना इंडिया इंपॉर्टेंट
Such statements will come.  US media
है। ऐसी स्टेटमेंट्स आएंगी। यूएस मीडिया
may also become a little hostile
भी हो सकता है कि थोड़ा सा होस्टाइल हो
against India.  But right now the US has
जाए अगेंस्ट इंडिया। बट अभी खैर यूएस ने
chosen this path.  Even if you
यही रास्ता चुना है। इन द पास्ट भी आप अगर
look into the past, whatever dictators have come to Pakistan, the
देखो तो पाकिस्तान में जो भी डिक्टेटर आए
US has welcomed them very much.
हैं यूएस ने उनको काफी वेलकम किया है।
Called to the White House.  Gave a lot of respect.   It
वाइट हाउस में बुलाया। काफी सम्मान दिया।
seems that Asim Munir will also go to the US very soon
लग रहा है कि आसिम मुनीर भी बहुत जल्दी
and he will be welcomed in the same manner there too.
यूएस जाएगा और वहां पर भी उसको इसी तरीके
All this is going to
से वेलकम किया जाएगा। ऑल दिस इज़ गोइंग टू
happen.  But in the end it remains to be seen whether the
हैपन। बट इन द एंड देखना यह होगा कि क्या
US will regret this policy or not.
यूएस यह पॉलिसी रिग्रेट करेगा या नहीं।
Because the country they are supporting has a
क्योंकि जिस कंट्री का यह साथ दे रहे हैं,
proven track record of
इस कंट्री का प्रूवन ट्रैक रिकॉर्ड है कि
supporting terrorists.  So
यह आतंकवादियों का समर्थन करता है। तो आने
in the coming times, you will see very strange scenes.
वाले समय में देखिए बहुत ही विचित्र दृश्य
Asim Anil will go to US.
देखने को मिलेंगे। आसिम अनिल यूएस जाएगा।
It will have a very grand welcome.  Trump will
काफी इसका भव्य वेलकम होगा। ट्रंप इसका
welcome this and it seems USA has
वेलकम करेंगे एंड लग रहा है यूएसए ने
decided what to do.  So this is
डिसाइड कर लिया इनको क्या करना है। सो दिस
interesting.  But again, we
इज़ इंटरेस्टिंग। बट अगेन हमने भी जो
still stand by the decision we took to put this Soul Treaty into absence.
में डालने का हम उस पर अभी भी खड़े हैं।
Many of Pakistan's air bases have been
पाकिस्तान के कई जो एयर बेसेस हैं
destroyed and Pakistan is
डिस्ट्रॉय हो चुके हैं और पाकिस्तान दर-दर
searching from door to door to get a good air defence
ढूंढ रहा है कि इनको कोई एक एयर डिफेंस
system because HQ
सिस्टम बढ़िया मिल जाए क्योंकि एच क्यू
Nine is not working.  Overall India has the
नाइन काम कर नहीं रहा। ओवरऑल इंडिया हैज़
upper hand.  But what has to be seen here is
दी अप्पर हैंड। बट देखना यह होगा यहां पर
that since US has now become so pro-Pakistan.
कि सिंस यूएस अब इतना प्रो पाकिस्तान हो
So tomorrow when we resume Operation Sindoor
चुका है। तो कल को जब ऑपरेशन सिंदूर हम
then
रिज्यूम करते हैं तब उस वक्त यूएसए की
what statements will come from USA at that time.  That will be very
क्या स्टेटमेंट्स आएंगी। दैट विल बी वेरी
interesting to see whether the US all together will
इंटरेस्टिंग टू सी क्या यूएस ऑल टुगेदर
start spoiling its relations with India
इंडिया के साथ रिलेशंस खराब करना शुरू कर
for the sake of Pakistan and not this will be
देगा फॉर द सेक ऑफ़ पाकिस्तान और नॉट दिस
very interesting to see. There will be
विल बी वेरी इंटरेस्टिंग टू सी अभी कुछ
many developments related to this to come.
इससे रिलेटेड डेवलपमेंट्स आएंगी बहुत सारी
I will make updated videos for you all.
आई विल मेक अपडेटेड वीडियोस फॉर यू ऑल
See, sometime go to any website
देखिए कभी किसी ऐसी वेबसाइट पे जाइएगा
where companies post jobs and you will
जहां पर कंपनीज़ जॉब पोस्ट करती हैं और आप
notice there that the demand for data analysts is
वहां पर नोट करेंगे डाटा एनालिस्ट की
continuously increasing.  Whether you are
डिमांड लगातार बढ़ती जा रही है। चाहे आप
in Mumbai, Delhi, Kolkata or
मुंबई में हो, दिल्ली में हो, कोलकाता में
anywhere, salaries obviously range based
हो, कहीं भी हो, सैलरीज ऑब्वियसली रेंज
on your experience.  But you
करती है आपके एक्सपीरियंस पे। मगर आप
can easily earn even Rs 50,600 per month from 2025.  Depending on your
भी कमा सकते हैं। डिपेंडिंग ऑन योर
experience, depending on your skills.  And the
एक्सपीरियंस, डिपेंडिंग ऑन योर स्किल। और
impact of data analysts is being
डाटा एनालिस्ट्स का इंपैक्ट हर इंडस्ट्री
seen in every industry.  It will obviously be seen in the corporate world.
में देखा जा रहा है। कॉर्पोरेट वर्ल्ड में
Apart from that,
ऑब्वियसली देखा जाएगा। उसके अलावा मेडिकल
articles are being published in medical science and even cricket.
साइंस में इवन क्रिकेट में आर्टिकल्स
This is a four day old
पब्लिश हो रहे हैं। यह इधर चार दिन पुराना
article about how data
आर्टिकल है कि किस तरीके से डाटा
analytics has transformed cricket all together.
एनालिटिक्स ने क्रिकेट को ऑल टुगेदर
I will tell you the reason.  Let
ट्रांसफॉर्म कर दिया है। रीजन मैं आपको
me show you for the first time
बताता हूं। मैं आपको पहली बार दिखाता हूं
how someone can present data if they have the skills of a data analyst.
पास आ जाए तो वह डाटा को कैसे प्रेजेंट कर
Once you have the
सकता है। एक बार आपके पास डाटा एनालिस्ट
skills of a data analyst, you can create all of these things.
की स्किल आ गई तो आप यह सब कुछ बना सकते
You will be able to see in what beautiful way the
हैं। आप देख पाओगे कितने खूबसूरत तरीके से
profit of a company and
आप एक कंपनी का प्रॉफिट एक कंपनी के किस
how much revenue a company earned in which month.
महीने में कितना रेवेन्यू गया। मार्केट
What is the market share?  This can be made in detail.
शेयर कितना है? ये डिटेल में बना सकते
Again it's not just like you
हैं। अगेन ये सिर्फ ऐसा नहीं है कि बस यू
just choose a color scheme and
नो आपने ये बस कलर स्कीम चूज़ करी और डाटा
enter the data.  In this, the formulas, the
डाल दिया। इसमें फार्मूलाज़ इसमें किस
way you enter the data, the way
तरीके से डाटा आप डालोगे, किस तरीके से
you present the data, everything matters.
डाटा आप प्रेजेंट करोगे सब कुछ मैटर करता
And companies today are
है। और कंपनीज़ आज के समय ऐसे लोगों को
ready to pay people who present the data to them in
पैसा देने के लिए तैयार हैं जो डाटा उनको
such a way and in such a form
इस तरीके से इस फॉर्म में उनके सामने
so that the companies can decide
प्रेजेंट करें ताकि कंपनीज़ डिसाइड कर पाए
what to do in the future.
कि फ्यूचर में उनको क्या करना है। फ्यूचर
Where do they want to go in the future?
में उनको कहां जाना है। करियर 247 का जो
With the help of Data Analysis course of Career 247,
डाटा एनालिस कोर्स है, इसकी मदद से ऑलरेडी
many of our students have already become capable of creating such projects.
कई हमारे स्टूडेंट्स ऐसे प्रोजेक्ट्स
I am showing you this project of one of our students
एक स्टूडेंट का आपको मैं प्रोजेक्ट दिखा
and this again is
रहा हूं और ये अगेन जो टोटल स्केल है उसका
just 5 to 6% of the total scale.  Apart from that, there are many other
बस 5 टू 6% है। उसके अलावा बहुत सारे और
tools in Data Analytics
टूल्स होते हैं डेटा एनालिटिक्स में
in which if you become proficient, then suddenly
जिसमें आप अगर प्रोफिशिएंट बन गए तो सडनली
your value will increase a lot in the job market.
जॉब मार्केट में आपकी वैल्यू बहुत ज्यादा
What do you simply have to do?
बढ़ जाएगी। आपको सिंपली क्या करना है? इस
Go to the comment section of this video.
वीडियो के यहां पे कमेंट सेक्शन में जाओ।
Click on the link here.  They will ask you for your name,
यहां पे लिंक पर क्लिक करो। अपना नाम,
email ID, number and discount code.  Please
ईमेल आईडी, नंबर और यहां पे डिस्काउंट कोड
put PG10 here.
आपसे मांगेंगे। यहां पे पीजी10 डाल देना।
No, otherwise you will be charged more money later
नहीं नहीं तो बाद में आपसे ज्यादा पैसे
for this course.  Make
चार्ज किए जाएंगे इस कोर्स के लिए। मेक
sure to add the discount code PD10 and
श्योर टू ऐड द डिस्काउंट कोड पीडी10 और
you will receive a call from a Career 247 consultant.
करियर 247 के कंसलटेंट की तरफ से आपको कॉल
You can ask them the question that
आएगा। आप उनसे सवाल पूछ सकते हैं कि किस
how can you start your career as a
तरीके से अपना करियर आप स्टार्ट कर सकते
Data Analyst?  So with this note,
हैं एस ए डाटा एनालिस्ट? सो इसी नोट के
this is the end of the video.  And thank you for
साथ यह है वीडियो का अंत। एंड थैंक यू फॉर
listening.  and as always say may the gods watch
लिसनिंग। एंड एज ऑलवेज से मे द गॉडज वॉच
over
ओवर